Welcome to our training on how to apply
to sell a restricted product category or brand.
There are a few steps you should take
before listing a product in the Amazon store.
First, confirm that it's okay to sell.
Make sure it's safe and complies
with all laws and regulations.
You should also review Amazon's restricted product
and product compliance policies
to verify that it isn't prohibited by Amazon
and meets all product-specific requirements.
Next, determine if the product requires any approvals.
Although products can be listed
in the Amazon store without approval,
we require approval to list certain products,
categories, and brands enrolled in Amazon brand registry.
You can obtain approval to sell a product, category,
or a registered brand by completing
a selling application in Seller Central.
An application may include document requests,
performance checks, and other qualifications.
It's designed to help ensure that customers can shop
with confidence in the Amazon store,
knowing that products are safe and authentic.
How will you know if your product requires an approval?
We've built approval checks and applications
right into the listing process.
To list a product that's already sold in the Amazon store,
open the Seller Central main menu,
hover over Catalog, and click Add Products.
Search for your product using a product ID.
You can also search by using a GTIN, like UPC, ISBN,
EAN, or JAN.
Or search using an ASIN, or other ID,
paired with descriptive information,
like brand or product name.
Next, locate the product you want to sell
in the search results.
If it requires approval,
you'll see a Show Limitations link,
which you can click to get a summary
of listing requirements.
Review the requirements and select a product condition
using the drop-down menu.
Click the Apply to Sell button,
and then the button on the Selling Application page
to begin the approval process.
-
The specific selling application you'll need to complete
will depend on the product you're trying to list
and the type of approval you need to secure.
Let's review a selling application for a category first,
then a Selling Application for a registered brand.
On the Selling Application for category page,
start by answering any product-related questions,
then review the list of requirements
for the purchase invoice you'll need to upload.
Check each box after you verify that your document
meets that requirement.
The purchase invoice you submit must be dated
within 180 days and include your name and address,
matching the information in your selling account.
It must also include the name and address
of the product's manufacturer or distributor,
and show a combined purchase of at least 10 units.
That means the invoice should show a paid balance
for at least 10 units,
demonstrating that you own the inventory.
If you're omitting the pricing for individual items
on your invoice, check the box to confirm.
Then check the box acknowledging that we may verify
your document by contacting the manufacturer
or distributor it identifies.
After checking each required box,
upload your purchase invoice.
Make sure it's a high-resolution PDF file
in the correct orientation.
Then provide any optional comment
that might help us assess your application,
along with contact information we can use
to ask follow-up questions.
Select Submit to complete the application.
-
If you need to complete a selling application
for a brand enrolled in brand registry,
you'll follow a similar process.
-
On the Selling application for brand page,
select the document type you want to upload
as part of your application.
Either a purchase invoice for products from the brand
that you received from a manufacturer or distributor,
or a letter directly from the brand
authorizing you to sell their products.
For a purchase invoice, you'll need to submit a document
that meets the same requirements we reviewed
for a category approval.
For an authorization letter,
you'll need to submit a document that is dated
within 180 days and includes your name and address,
matching the information in your selling account.
Your letter also needs to be on the brand's letterhead
and include the name and address of the brand.
Make sure it's a high-resolution PDF file
in the correct orientation.
After uploading either document,
you'll provide contact information,
plus any optional comments.
Then select Submit to complete the application.
When you submit a selling application for a brand
enrolled in brand registry,
you're requesting approval to match offers
to the brand's existing product detail pages.
This approval doesn't provide you
with additional listing privileges
to create or edit product detail pages for the brand,
or access to brand selling benefits like stores
and A+ content.
Those privileges and benefits are reserved for sellers
internal to the brand and authorized third-party resellers.
If you'd like more information
about requesting additional listing privileges
and brand selling benefits,
see our Seller University video,
Request Access to Brand Selling Benefits.
Now that you know how to request an approval
for a product that's already sold in the Amazon store,
let's review how to request approval for a new product.
You'll start the process the same way,
double checking that there's no existing listing
for your item.
Search for the product using the Product Adding tool.
If it doesn't appear in the search results,
click the Create a New Listing button.
During the listing creation process,
you'll find out if your new product
requires a category approval when you select a product type.
If it does, you'll see Learn More Text
and a Lock icon next to that category.
Click the text to open the categories and products
that require approval help page.
Then find and click the Request Approval link.
Next to the relevant product category.
This will bring you to the Selling Application
for category page, which you can complete
using the same steps we reviewed earlier.
You'll find out if you need to complete
a selling application for a registered brand
a little later in the listing creation process
while entering information for the new product detail page.
After entering or selecting the brand's name
in the brand name field, you'll receive error 5461.
Use the link in the error message
to access the Selling Application
for Catalog Authorization page
where you'll request approval to list and sell
the item for the brand.
As part of the application,
you'll provide a letter of authorization from the brand
as well as product information and images
to create the new ASIN and product detail page.
Note that this is the only scenario
in which a seller other than the brand owner
or another seller granted listing privileges
for the brand can apply to create a new listing
for a brand enrolled in brand registry.
After completing a selling application for a product,
category or brand, you'll receive confirmation
within 24 hours that we're reviewing your approval request.
In most cases, that review process
is completed within three business days.
To monitor the status of a selling application,
open the Seller Central Main Menu,
hover over Catalog and click View Selling Applications.
After the status of an application is approved,
select List Products to start adding
that product to your inventory.
For more tips on submitting a selling application,
review the picture requirements for when you apply to sell
and invoice requirements for when you apply to sell
videos in Seller University.
This concludes our training on how to apply to sell products,
categories or brands that require approval to sell.
Continue to the next video in the series to learn our tips
for complying with Amazon's product detail page policies
or resolving violations.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon Store.